#HI removed, cleaned
#and corrected by Tronar
Your father has proved
to be an awful traitor.
The girl is innocent.
She should be given a chance
to prove her loyalty.
You must write
to Lady Catelyn.
If you would help your father,
urge your brother
to keep the king's peace.
Tell him to come
to King's Landing,
and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
You're sure this is
the only copy in Winterfell?
Daenerys is not her father.
And she never will be.
With the right counsel.
I am her hand, not her head.
I can't make
her decisions for her.
You need to find a way
to make her listen.
- It's called Longclaw.
- It was my father's sword.
It was meant for my son, Jorah.
He brought dishonor
to our house,
but he had the grace to leave
the sword before he fled
from Westeros.
Clegane, look into the flames.
What do you see?
There's a mountain.
Looks like an arrowhead.
The dead are marching past.
Thousands of 'em.
Cersei thinks
the army of the dead
is nothing but a story.
What if we prove her wrong,
bring one of these things
down to King's Landing
and show her the truth?
We're all on the same side.
We're all breathin'.
- You all right?
- Mm.
Ever been north before?
Never seen snow before.
Beautiful, eh?
I can breathe again.
Down south, the air
smells like pig shit.
You've never been
down south.
- I've been to Winterfell.
- That's the North.
How do you live up here?
How do you keep your balls
from freezing off?
- You got to keep moving.
- That's the secret.
Walking's good, fighting's
better, fucking's best.
There's not a living woman
within a hundred miles of here.
We have to make do
with what we've got.
This one is maybe
not so smart.
Davos says
he's a strong fighter.
Good. That's more important
than being smart.
Smart people don't come up
here looking for the dead.
So, you met
this Dragon Queen, huh?
And?
She'll only fight beside
us if I bend the knee.
You spent too much time
with the Free Folk.
Now you don't
like kneeling.
Mance Rayder
was a brave man.
A proud man.
The King-beyond-the-Wall
never bent the knee.
How many of his people
died for his pride?
You still mad at us, boy?
You sold me to a witch.
A priestess.
I'll admit,
it is a subtle distinction.
We're fighting a great war.
Wars cost money.
I wanted to be
one of you.
I wanted to join the
Brotherhood, but you sold me off
like a slave.
Do you know
what she did to me?
She strapped me
down on a bed,
- she stripped me naked...
- Sounds all right so far.
- ...and put leeches on me.
- Was she naked, too?
She needed your blood.
Yes, thank you.
I know that.
- Could have been worse.
- She wanted to kill me!
- They would have killed me if wasn't for Davos.
- But they didn't, did they?
So, what you
whinging about?
I'm not whinging.
Your lips are moving and you're
complaining about something.
That's whinging.
This one's been
killed six times.
You don't hear him
bitching about it.
Good lad.
The first time I went north of
the Wall was with your father.
He was a good man.
He deserved a better son.
Were you with him
at the end?
I was a prisoner
of the wildlings.
But we avenged him.
I want you to know that.
Every mutineer
found justice.
Can't think of a worse
way for him to go.
The Night's Watch
was his life.
He would have died to protect
every one of those men.
And they butchered him.
I hate that
he died that way.
My father was the most
honorable man I ever met.
He was good
all the way through.
And he died on
the executioner's block.
Your father wanted
to execute me, you know?
I heard.
He was in the right,
of course.
Didn't make me
hate him any less.
- I'm glad he didn't catch you.
- Me, too.
Your father
gave me this sword.
Changed the pommel
from a bear to a wolf...
but it's still Longclaw.
Lord Commander Mormont
thought you'd never
come back to Westeros.
But you are back,
and it's been in your
family for centuries.
It's not right
for me to have it.
He gave it to you.
I'm not his son.
I brought shame
onto my house.
I broke
my father's heart.
I forfeited the right
to claim this sword.
It's yours.
May it serve you well...
and your children
after you.
Father used to watch us
from up here.
He wouldn't say much.
You probably
don't remember.
You were inside
knitting all the time.
I remember.
One time, the boys were shooting
arrows with Ser Rodrik.
I came out here after,
and Bran had
left his bow behind,
just lying on the ground.
Ser Rodrik would have
cuffed him if he saw.
There was one arrow
in the target.
There was no one around,
just like now.
No one to stop me.
So I started shooting.
And every shot,
I had to go up there
and get my one arrow and walk
back and shoot it again.
I wasn't very good.
Finally,
I hit the bull's-eye.
Could have been
the 20th shot or the 50th.
I don't remember.
But I hit the bull's-eye,
and I heard this.
I looked up,
and he's standing
right here,
smiling down at me.
I knew what I was doing
was against the rules.
But he was smiling,
so I knew it wasn't wrong.
The rules were wrong.
I was doing what I was meant
to be doing, and he knew it.
Now he's dead.
Killed by the Lannisters
with your help.
What?
That's your
pretty handwriting.
Septa Mordane
used to crack my knuckles
'cause I couldn't write
as well as you.
"Robb, I write to you today
with heavy heart.
Our good King Robert
is dead,
killed from wounds
he took in a boar hunt."
You don't have to read it.
I remember.
"Father has been
charged with treason.
He conspired with Robert's brothers
against my beloved Joffrey
and tried to steal
his throne.
The Lannisters
are treating me well
and providing me
with every comfort.
I beg you,
come to King's Landing,
swear fealty
to King Joffrey,
and prevent any strife
between the great houses
of Lannister and Stark.
Your faithful sister,
Sansa."
They forced me to do it.
Did they?
With a knife
at your throat?
Did they put you
on a rack and stretch you
until your bones
started to pop?
You don't know what it was like.
I was a child.
So was I. I would have let them kill
me before I betrayed my family.
They told me it was
the only way to save Father.
And you were stupid enough
to believe them.
I remember you standing on that
platform with Joffrey and Cersei
when they dragged
Father to the block.
I remember the pretty dress
you were wearing.
I remember the fancy way
you did your hair.
You were there?
I was there.
Standing in the crowd
near Baelor's statue.
And what did you do?
Did you come
running to the rescue?
Did you fight off the
Lannisters and save Father?
- I wanted to.
- But you didn't, just like me.
I didn't betray him.
I didn't betray Robb.
I didn't betray our entire
family for my beloved Joffrey.
You should be on your
knees, thanking me.
We're standing in Winterfell
again because of me.
You didn't win it back,
Jon didn't win it back.
He lost the Battle
of the Bastards.
The Knights of the Vale
won the battle,
and they rode north
for me.
While you were off, where?
Traveling the world?
- I was training.
- Training.
Well, while
you were training,
I suffered things
you could never imagine.
Oh, I don't know about that.
I can imagine quite a lot.
You never would have
survived what I survived.
I guess we'll never know.
What are you going to do
with that letter?
I don't know yet.
Who did you show it to?
Where did you find it?
You're scared,
aren't you?
What are you scared of?
You didn't commit
any crimes.
- No one's going to hang you.
- Well, Arya...
You're scared I'll show it
to Jon and he'll be angry.
No, that's not Jon.
He'll understand.
You were just
a scared little girl,
all alone with
the wicked Lannisters.
Do you know how happy Cersei would
be right now if she saw us fighting?
This is exactly
what she wants.
This is what she's always
wanted... to tear us apart.
You're scared the Northern
lords will read it.
They wouldn't think much
of Lady Sansa
if they knew how she did
Cersei's bidding.
What would little
Lyanna Mormont say?
She's younger than you were
when you wrote this.
Are you going to say,
"But I was just a child?"
You're angry.
Sometimes anger makes people
do unfortunate things.
Sometimes fear makes them
I'll go with anger.
You're the one
they call "the Dog."
Fuck off.
They told me
you were mean.
Were you born mean
or you just hate wildings?
I don't give two shits
about wildings.
It's gingers I hate.
Gingers are beautiful.
We are kissed by fire,
just like you.
Don't point
your fucking finger at me.
Did you trip into the fire
when you were a baby?
I didn't trip,
I was pushed.
And ever since,
you've been mean.
Will you fuck off?
I don't think
you're truly mean.
You have sad eyes.
You want to suck my dick,
is that it?
- Dick?
- Cock.
Ah, dick.
I like it.
I bet you do.
Nope, it's pussy for me.
I have a beauty waiting for me
back at Winterfell.
If I ever get back there.
Yellow hair, blue eyes,
the tallest woman
you've ever seen.
Almost as tall as you.
- Brienne of Tarth.
- You know her?
You're with Brienne
of fucking Tarth?
Well, not with her yet.
- But I see the way she looks at me.
- How does she look at you?
Like she wants to carve you
up and eat your liver?
You do know her.
We've met.
I want to make
babies with her.
Think of them...
great big monsters.
They'd conquer the world.
How did a mad fucker
like you live this long?
I'm good
at killing people.
You don't look
much like him.
Who's that?
Your father.
I suppose you favor
your mother.
You knew him?
'Course I did.
When he was Hand,
he sent me off hunting
for the Mountain.
Your wildling friend
told me
the red woman
brought you back.
Thoros has brought
me back six times.
We both serve
the same lord.
I serve the North.
The North didn't
raise you from the dead.
The Lord of Light
never spoke to me.
I don't know
anything about him.
what he wants from me.
- He wants you alive.
- Why?
I don't know.
That's all anyone can
tell me... "I don't know."
So, what's the point
in serving a god
if none of us knows
what he wants?
I think about that
all the time.
I don't think it's our
purpose to understand.
Except one thing...
we're soldiers.
We have to know
what we're fighting for.
I'm not fighting so some
man or woman I barely know
can sit on a throne
made of swords.
So, what are you
fighting for?
Life.
Death is the enemy.
The first enemy
and the last.
But we all die.
The enemy always wins.
And we still need
to fight him.
That's all I know.
You and I won't find much
joy while we're here,
but we can keep
others alive.
We can defend those
who can't defend themselves.
"I am the shield that
guards the realms of men."
Maybe we don't need to
understand any more than that.
Maybe that's enough.
Aye.
That's what I saw
in the fire.
A mountain
like an arrowhead.
Are you sure?
We're getting close.
Do you know
what I like about you?
- I honestly don't.
- You're not a hero.
Oh.
Well, I've been heroic
on occasion.
I once charged through the Mud
Gate of King's Landing and...
I don't want you
to be a hero.
Heroes do stupid things
and they die.
Drogo, Jorah, Daario,
even this...
Jon Snow...
they all try
to outdo each other.
Who can do the stupidest,
bravest thing.
It's interesting,
these heroes you name.
Drogo, Jorah, Daario,
even this...
Jon Snow.
They all
fell in love with you.
- Jon Snow's not in love with me.
- Oh, my mistake.
I suppose he stares
at you longingly
because he's hopeful for a
successful military alliance.
He's too little for me.
I didn't mean...
As heroes go,
he is quite little.
I know you're brave.
I wouldn't have chosen
a coward as my Hand.
So, if all goes well,
I'll finally get
to meet your sister.
From everything
you've told me about her,
she'd rather murder me
than speak with me.
Oh, first, she'd torture
you in some horrible way,
then she'd murder you.
Nobody trusts my sister
less than I do, believe me.
But if we go
to the capital,
we'll go with two armies,
we'll go with three dragons.
Anyone touches you, King's Landing
burns down to the foundation stones.
And right now, she's thinking
of how to set a trap.
Of course she is.
And she's wondering what
trap you're laying for her.
Are we?
Laying any traps?
If we want to create
a new and better world,
I'm not sure deceit and mass
murder is the best way to start.
Which war was won without
deceit and mass murder?
Yes, you'll need
to be ruthless
if you're going
to win the throne.
You need to inspire
a degree of fear.
But fear
is all Cersei has.
It's all my father had,
and Joffrey.
It makes
their power brittle
because everyone beneath them
longs to see them dead.
Aegon Targaryen got
quite a long way on fear.
He did.
But you once spoke to me
of breaking the wheel.
Aegon built a wheel.
If that's the kind of queen
you want to be,
how are you different from all the
other tyrants that came before you?
So we walk
into the lions' den.
My brother promised me
he'd keep a grip
on the Lannister forces.
Forgive me, but I don't care
about any Lannister promises.
Except yours.
And I promised him
I'd keep you from doing
anything impulsive.
Impulsive?
This will be
a difficult negotiation.
We're sitting down with people who
want to see us both headless.
My sister is likely to say
something provocative.
- And?
- And you have been known
to lose your temper
from time to time,
as all great leaders do.
When have I lost
my temper?
Burning the Tarlys,
for instance.
That was not impulsive.
That was necessary.
- Perhaps.
- Perhaps?
Perhaps the father
needed to die and not the son.
Perhaps they both needed time
to contemplate their mistakes
in the solitude
of a cold cell.
We had no time to discuss
the possibilities
before you ended
their possibilities.
One could be forgiven
for thinking you're taking
your family's side
in this debate.
I am taking their side.
You need to take
your enemy's side
if you're going to see
things the way they do.
And you need to see things
the way they do
if you're going to
anticipate their actions,
respond effectively,
and beat them.
Which I want you
to do very much.
Because I believe in you and in
the world you want to build.
But the world
you want to build
doesn't get built
all at once.
Probably not
in a single lifetime.
How do we ensure
that your vision endures?
After you break the wheel, how
do we make sure it stays broken?
You want to know who sits on the
Iron Throne after I'm dead.
Is that it?
You say you can't
have children,
but there are other ways
of choosing a successor.
The Night's Watch
has one method.
The ironborn, for all their
many flaws, have another.
We will discuss the succession
after I wear the crown.
Your Grace, I saw
hundreds of arrows
fly towards you when you
fought on the Blackwater Rush,
and I saw hundreds
of arrows miss.
But any one of them could have
found your heart and ended your...
You've been thinking about my
death quite a bit, haven't you?
Is this one of the items
you discussed
with your brother
in King's Landing?
I'm trying to serve you
by planning for the long term.
Perhaps if you planned
for the short term,
we wouldn't have lost
Dorne and Highgarden.
We will discuss the succession
after I wear the crown.
Look!
A bear.
Big fucker.
Do bears have blue eyes?
We have to get him
back to Eastwatch.
Flask.
Go on.
You all right?
I just got bit
by a dead bear.
Aye, you did.
Funny old life.
Right, then.
We're off.
- Where did she get it?
- I don't know.
She seems
very resourceful.
You're worried.
We're asking 20,000 men
to fight with us in the worst
winter any of them have ever seen.
The weather will be
the least of their problems.
Many of them will be happy to
find a good reason to go home.
- You question their loyalty?
- Their loyalty is to Jon.
Jon is not here. I haven't
heard from him in weeks.
You're the Lady
of Winterfell.
The king chose you
to rule in his absence.
And rule you have.
Wisely, ably.
They see that.
They respect you.
Some may even prefer you.
Yes, they turned
their backs on Jon
when it was time
to retake Winterfell,
then they named him
their king,
and now they're ready to turn
their backs on him again.
How far would you trust
men like that?
They're all
bloody wind vanes.
If they found out
that I wrote that letter,
a woman who's
already married
not one, but two enemies
of her house...
By the time Jon comes back,
he'll have no army left.
Arya's not like them.
She's your sister.
You may have
disagreements,
but she would never
betray her family.
She would if she thought
I was going to betray Jon.
Is that what she thinks?
I don't know
what she thinks.
I don't know her anymore.
Perhaps Lady Brienne
could help.
She's sworn to protect
both of Catelyn Stark's girls,
is she not?
She is.
And if one of you were planning
to harm the other in any way,
wouldn't she be
honor bound to intercede?
She would.
- Something I've always wanted to know.
- All right.
How drunk were you when you charged
through the breach on Pyke?
If I'm being honest, I don't remember
charging through the breach.
Some of the lads told me
about it the next morning.
Sounded like
a good scrap.
Aye.
It was a proper scrap.
The ironborn thought
you were some kind of god,
the way you were waving
that flaming sword.
I thought you were
the bravest man I ever saw.
Just the drunkest.
Where's the rest of them?
If we wait long enough,
we'll find out.
Run back to Eastwatch.
Get a raven to Daenerys,
tell her what's happened.
- I'm not leaving you.
- You're the fastest. Go, now.
You're faster without the hammer.
Give it.
Give it!
- Come on!
- Run!
Come on!
Stop!
Go!
What happened?
Where are the others?
Raven, we need
to send a raven.
Get the maester, now!
Thoros?
Thoros.
They say it's one
of the better ways to go.
Lord of Light,
show us the way.
Come to us in our darkness and
lead Your servant into the light.
We have to burn his body.
We'll all be
close behind him
unless the Lord of Light is kind
enough to send us a bit of fire.
Lord of Light,
come to us
in our darkness,
for the night is dark
and full of terrors.
We'll all freeze soon.
And so will the water.
When you killed
the white walker,
almost all the dead
that followed it fell.
Why?
Maybe he was the one
who turned them.
We can go
for the walkers.
Maybe we'll stand a chance.
No.
We need to take
that thing back with us.
There's a raven flying
for Dragonstone now.
Daenerys is
our only chance.
No.
There's another.
Kill him.
He turned them all.
You don't understand.
The Lord
brought you back.
He brought me back.
No one else.
Just us.
Did He do it to watch us
freeze to death?
Careful, Beric.
You lost your priest.
This is your last life.
I've been waiting for the
end for a long time.
Maybe the Lord brought
me here to find it.
Every lord I've ever
met's been a cunt.
Don't see why the Lord of Light
should be any different.
My lady.
My lady?
It's an invitation
to King's Landing.
My lady, you are
the Lady of Winterfell.
I am, and you will
represent my interests
at this gathering
as you see them.
They invited you.
They want you there.
I will not set foot
in King's Landing
while Cersei Lannister
is queen.
If they want
another Stark prisoner,
they can come
and take me.
Until then, I'll remain
where I belong.
I have work to do here.
It's not safe.
Ser Jaime will be there.
You said he treated you
honorably before.
I'm not worried about me.
It's not safe leaving you
with Littlefinger.
I have many guards
who would happily
imprison him
or behead him
whether or not
you're here.
And you trust
their loyalty?
You trust he hasn't been speaking
to them all behind your back?
Let me at least leave Podrick
behind to watch over you.
He has become
a competent swordsman...
I do not need to be watched
over or minded or cared for.
I'm not a child,
I am the Lady of Winterfell,
and I am home.
This is the safest
place for me.
My lady,
I swore an oath to protect
you and your sister.
- If I abandon you...
- The trip to King's Landing is long, Lady Brienne,
and you won't be
traveling on summer roads.
The sooner you leave, the better
your chances of making it on time.
Yes, my lady.
You can't.
The most important
person in the world
can't fly off to the most
dangerous place in the world.
- Who else can?
- No one.
They knew the risks
when they left.
You can't win the throne
if you're dead.
You can't break the wheel
So, what would
you have me do?
Nothing.
Sometimes nothing
is the hardest thing to do.
If you die,
we're all lost.
Everyone, everything.
You told me to do nothing
before and I listened to you.
I'm not doing
nothing again.
Dumb cunt.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck it.
Yah!
Fall back!
- Fall back!
- Come on!
Help me!
Go!
Jon!
Go now! Leave!
Uncle Benjen!
How?
- You ride for the pass.
- Come with me.
There's no time.
Go!
We'll meet again,
Clegane.
Fucking hope not.
It's time to go,
Your Grace.
A bit longer.
Rider approaching!
Open the gate!
Not what
you're looking for?
I have hundreds of men here at
Winterfell, all loyal to me.
They're not here now.
What are these?
My faces.
Where did you get them?
In Braavos, while I was
training to be a Faceless Man.
What does that mean?
Back in Braavos,
before I got
my first face,
there was a game
I used to play.
The Game of Faces.
It's simple...
I ask you a question
about yourself,
and you try to make lies
sound like the truth.
If you fool me, you win.
If I catch a lie,
you lose.
Let's play.
I don't want to play.
How do you feel
about Jon being king?
Is there someone else you think
should rule the North instead of him?
Those faces,
what are they?
You want to do
the asking?
Are you sure?
The Game of Faces
didn't turn out so well
for the last person
who asked me questions.
Tell me what they are.
We both wanted to be other
people when we were younger.
You wanted to be a queen,
to sit next to a handsome,
young king on the Iron Throne.
I wanted to be a knight,
to pick up a sword like
Father and go off to battle.
Neither of us got to be
that other person, did we?
The world doesn't just let girls
decide what they're going to be.
But I can now.
With the faces,
I can choose.
I can become
someone else.
Speak in their voice,
live in their skin.
I could even become you.
I wonder what
it would feel like
to wear
those pretty dresses...
to be the Lady
of Winterfell.
All I'd need
to find out...
is your face.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I wish I could
take it back.
I wish we'd never gone.
I don't.
If we hadn't gone,
I wouldn't have seen.
You have to see it
to know.
Now I know.
The dragons
are my children.
They're the only children
I'll ever have.
Do you understand?
We are going to destroy
the Night King and his army.
And we'll do it together.
You have my word.
Thank you, Dany.
"Dany"?
Who was the last person
who called me that?
I'm not sure.
Was it my brother?
Mm, not the company
you want to keep.
All right.
Not "Dany."
How about "my queen"?
I'd, uh,
bend the knee, but...
What about those
who swore allegiance to you?
They'll all come to see
you for what you are.
I hope I deserve it.
You do.
You should get some rest.
There is only one war
that matters. And it is here.